Inventory of the Edward H. Forney papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Edward H. Forney papers
1942-1964
65022
Hoover Institution Archives
7 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (2.6 linear feet)
Handwritten notes, correspondence, course writings, orders, reports, news releases, and news clippings relating primarily to the Korean and Vietnam Wars.
Forney, Edward H.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1965.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the library catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Edward H. Forney was a colonel, deputy chief of staff, and brigadier general in the United States Marine Corps, a senior advisor to the Republic of Korea (ROK) Marine Corps, and a scholar.
Scope and Content of Collection
The Edward H. Forney papers contain handwritten notes (some in small notebooks), correspondence (including family letters), course writings, orders, reports, news releases, and news clippings relating primarily to the Korean and Vietnam Wars. Forney took numerous history courses about World War I, World War II, military operations in Europe and in the Pacific, psychological warfare, post-war problems, Soviet foreign policy (1918-1939), U.S. foreign policy, French military contributions in the American Revolution War, and the North Atlantic Treaty Organization. As brigadier general for the U.S. Marine Corps, Forney kept up-to-date about foreign relations among China, Southeast Asia, the Soviet Union, the United States, Korea, Vietnam, and France, as revealed in his extensive news file.
United States. Marine Corps--Officers.; China--Foreign relations.; China--Politics and government--20th century.; China--Politics and government.; Guerrilla warfare.; Korea--History.; Korea--Politics and government.; Korean War, 1950-1953.; Laos--Foreign relations--United States.; Soviet Union--Foreign relations--United States.; Soviet Union--Politics and government.; United States--Foreign relations--Laos.; United States--Politics and government.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975.; Vietnam--History.; Vietnam--Politics and government.
- Biographical File, 1950-1963
  - Handwritten notes, 1957 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Handwritten notes, undated (Box-folder 1: 2-6)
  - "Brig. Gen. Edward H. Forney, United States Marine Corps," photograph, undated (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - Correspondence, 1950, 1954, 1957, 1963 (Box-folder 1: 8)
    Scope and Contents note
    Personal family letters.
- Course File, 1956-1960
  Coursework and review sheets from various history courses taken by Forney.
  - Harvard Business Review, 1956-1960 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - History 175, undated (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - History 176, undated (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - History 127, 1956 (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - History 128, undated (Box-folder 1: 13)
  - History 191, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 1: 14)
  - History 192, undated (Box-folder 1: 15)
  - Unidentified course materials, undated (Box-folder 1: 16)
  - Historiography 287, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 1: 17)
  - "History of the Flags of the NATO Countries," manuscript, 1956 (Box-folder 1: 18)
  - "The National Identity Card Program, the Federation of Malaya: A Research Report," by E. H. Adkins, Jr., Michigan State University Viet Nam Advisory Group in Collaboration with Public Safety Division, United States Operations Mission to Viet Nam, 1961 (Box-folder 6: 1)
- Korean War File, 1942, 1950-1958
  - Hymns, circa 1950 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - "Map Used by Brig. Gen. Edward Forney, United States Marine Corps, During the Korean War,", circa 1950-1953 (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - "Chronology of the Defense,", circa 1950-1953 (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - Amphibious Training Command, Pacific Fleet documents, 1942, 1950, 1951 (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - Photocopies of bibliography index cards, 1950-1957 (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - Photocopies of correspondence, organization description, annual report, and information for mail pertaining to the Holy Mother's Social Charity Work Catholic Organization, 1958 (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - Reports, 1952, 1955-1958 (Box-folder 2: 7)
- Vietnam War File, 1962, 1964
  - Reports, 1962 (Box-folder 2: 8)
  - Reports, 1964 (Box-folder 2: 9)
- Miscellaneous File, 1944-1964
  - "The March of the XX Corps from St. Jacques to Verdun, France: 600 Miles in 30 Days, One of the Fastest Sustained Marches in History," map, 1944 (Box-folder 5: 23)
  - Plastic arrows, circa 1950-1953 (Box-folder 5: 24)
    Plastic arrows colored red and blue, assumed to be used on maps, stored in envelopes. Envelopes have writings about NKPA (North Korean People's Army) and EUSAK (Eighth United States Army in Korea).
  - Speeches, 1964 (Box-folder 5: 25)
  - Sports pamphlet, undated (Box-folder 5: 26)
  - "From The Adventures of My Grandfather, by John Lewis Peyton, as Told to the Author by a Kentucky Frontiersman," transcript, undated (Box-folder 5: 27)
  - "Weather in the North Pacific" and two copies of "Safe Conduct Pass,", undated (Box-folder 5: 28)
- News File, 1951-1964
  - China/Chinese, clippings, 1951 (Box-folder 2: 10)
  - The Korean Republic, newspaper, 1957 (Box-folder 2: 11)
  - The Korea Times, newspaper, 1957 (Box-folder 2: 12)
  - The Korean Republic, newspaper, 1957 (Box-folder 2: 13)
  - Korean clippings, 1957 (Box-folder 2: 14)
  - The Korean Republic newspaper, 1957 (Box-folder 2: 15-16)
  - The Korea Times, clippings, 1957 (Box-folder 2: 17)
  - The Korean Republic, newspaper, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 2: 18-19)
  - The Korean Republic, clippings, 1957 (Box-folder 2: 20)
  - The Korea Times, clippings, 1958 (Box-folder 2: 21)
  - The Korean Republic, clippings, 1958 (Box-folder 2: 22)
  - Korea, general, clippings, 1958 (Box-folder 2: 23)
  - Republic of Korea Marines, clippings, 1958 (Box-folder 2: 24)
  - U.S. Marine Corps, clippings, 1958 (Box-folder 2: 25)
  - U.S. Fleet Marine, clippings, 1958 (Box-folder 2: 26)
  - U.S. President Dwight D. Eisenhower, clippings, 1959, 1962 (Box-folder 2: 27)
  - Education, clippings, 1960, 1961 (Box-folder 2: 28)
  - Ben G. Forney, clippings, 1961 (Box-folder 2: 29)
  - U.S. President John F. Kennedy, clippings, 1961 (Box-folder 2: 30)
  - "Art Treasures for All America," clippings, 1961 December 10 (Box-folder 2: 31)
  - "These Days" column, clippings, 1961, 1962 (Box-folder 2: 32)
  - Southeast Asia, clippings, 1961, 1962 (Box-folder 2: 33)
  - U.S. Marines, clippings, 1962 (Box-folder 2: 34)
  - China/Chinese, clippings, 1960, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - Soviet/Russian, clippings, 1961, 1963 (Box-folder 3: 2)
  - U.S. President John F. Kennedy, releases, 1961, 1963 (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - U.S. President John F. Kennedy, clippings, 1962, 1963 (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - U.S. President John F. Kennedy's assassination, clippings, 1963 (Box-folder 3: 5-7)
  - U.S. News & Report, clippings, 1963 November 18 (Box-folder 3: 8)
  - Releases, 1963 (Box-folder 3: 9)
  - Southeast Asia, clippings, 1963, 1964 (Box-folder 3: 10)
  - Robert S. McNamara, Clippings, 1961, 1963, 1964 (Box-folder 3: 11)
  - Brief announcements, clippings, 1963 (Box-folder 3: 12)
  - Mixed clippings, 1963 (Box-folder 3: 13)
  - Saigon Daily News, newspaper, 1963 (Box-folder 3: 14-15)
  - Time, magazine, 1963 (Box-folder 3: 16)
  - Le Journal, newspaper, 1963 (Box-folder 3: 17)
  - Time, magazine, 1963 (Box-folder 3: 18)
  - Vietnamese newspaper, 1963 (Box-folder 3: 19)
  - Saigon Daily News, newspaper, 1963 (Box-folder 3: 20)
  - Newsweek, magazine, 1963 (Box-folder 3: 21)
  - Vietnam War, general, clippings, 1961, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - Saigon Daily News, newspaper, 1963 (Box-folder 4: 2)
  - Vietnam War, releases, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 4: 3)
  - U.S. President Lyndon B. Johnson, clippings, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 4: 4)
  - Vietcong, clippings, 1963 (Box-folder 4: 5)
  - United Nations, clippings, 1964 (Box-folder 4: 6)
  - North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO), clippings, 1964 (Box-folder 4: 7)
  - "Worldgram," clippings, 1964 (Box-folder 4: 8)
  - Douglas MacArthur, clippings, 1964 (Box-folder 4: 9)
  - Saigon Daily News, newspaper, 1964 (Box-folder 4: 10)
  - France, clippings, 1964 (Box-folder 4: 11)
  - Saigon Daily News, newspaper, 1964 (Box-folder 4: 12)
  - Mixed clippings, 1964 (Box-folder 4: 13)
  - Capt. Robert Alan Phillips, clippings, 1964 (Box-folder 4: 14)
  - Catholicism/Buddhism, clippings, 1964 (Box-folder 4: 15)
  - Chesapeake Bay Bridge-Tunnel, clippings, 1964 (Box-folder 4: 16)
  - Saigon Daily News, newspaper, 1964 (Box-folder 4: 17-18)
  - Mixed clippings, 1964 (Box-folder 4: 19)
  - Saigon Daily News, newspaper, 1964 (Box-folder 4: 20)
  - The Saigon Post, newspaper, 1964 (Box-folder 4: 21)
  - U.S. News & World Report, clippings, 1964 April 27-June 15 (Box-folder 4: 22-27)
  - Southeast Asia Treaty Organization (SEATO), clippings, circa 1954 (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - Seoul recapture, clippings, circa 1957 (Box-folder 5: 2)
  - Gen. Trudeau, clippings, 1958 (Box-folder 5: 3)
  - Gen. McGee, clippings, 1958 (Box-folder 5: 4)
  - Naval Academy, clippings, 1958, circa 1962-1963 (Box-folder 5: 5)
  - President Mohammad Ayub Khan of Pakistan, clippings, circa 1958-1959 (Box-folder 5: 6)
  - Cuba, clippings, circa 1961-1962 (Box-folder 5: 7)
  - U.S. President John F. Kennedy's assassination, clippings, circa 1963, undated (Box-folder 5: 8)
  - Southeast Asia, clippings, circa 1961-1964 (Box-folder 5: 9)
  - Vietnam War, clippings, circa 1961-1964 (Box-folder 5: 10)
  - Vietnam, general, clippings, circa 1961-1964 (Box-folder 5: 11)
  - Wire reports, circa 1961-1964 (Box-folder 5: 12)
  - China/Chinese, clippings, circa 1961-1964 (Box-folder 5: 13)
  - Gen. Paul Harkins, clippings, circa 1962-1964 (Box-folder 5: 14)
  - Ambassadors, clippings, 1964 (Box-folder 5: 15)
  - Saigon Daily News, newspaper, 1964 (Box-folder 5: 16-17)
  - Civil War, clippings, undated (Box-folder 5: 18)
  - Booklet analysis, clippings, undated (Box-folder 5: 19)
  - Unidentified war, clippings, undated (Box-folder 5: 20)
  - Korea, mission work, clippings, undated (Box-folder 5: 21)
  - New appointments, clippings, undated (Box-folder 5: 22)
  - Press reviews related to the Vietnam War, bound volume, 1961 August-November (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - Press reviews related to the Vietnam War, bound volume, 1961 December - 1962 March (Box-folder 6: 3)
  - Press reviews related to the Vietnam War, bound volume, 1962 April-July (Box-folder 7: 1)
  - Press reviews related to the Vietnam War, bound volume, 1962 August-November (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - Scrapbook of news clippings related to the Vietnam War, 1960 August 5 - 1962 October 9 (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - Scrapbook of news clippings, wire reports, and news releases related to the Vietnam War, 1963 (Box-folder 8: 2)